上帝为男人和女人造了花园并且告诉他们...
God made a garden for Man and Woman and he told them...
"不要吃那树上的果."
'"Do not eat of the fruit from that tree.'"
一条蛇来到女人面前建议她摘树上的苹果.
A serpent visited the Woman and offered her an apple from the tree.
他告诉她苹果能给她带来知识.
He told her the apple would give her knowledge.
他非常有说服力...
He was very persuasive...
人类自此便多灾多难
and Mankind has been paying the price ever since.
全都是因为我们总强求一些我们根本不需要的东西
All because we were tempted by something we didn't need.
而蛇说出了历史上第一次的谎话
The serpent was the first grifter.
Terry,最近怎么样?又是我 Chazz啊
Yo,Terry,what's going on?It's Chazz again.
我今天下午就要那些货
'Ere what,yeah.I need those flaming boxes delivered this afternoon,drey.
你帮我安排一下拉 用辆车送过来
You can do that for me,just put them all in the van,yeah?
那就最好了
Yeah,that'll be great.
Terry,你要等一下 我妈妈打电话给我 我得先接一下
Yeah,Terry,gotta put you on hold,it's my mom on the other line.
可能她腰痛又犯了
Probably her hip again.One sec.
Hyotona先生,你好
Mr.Hyotona,konnichiwa.
那文物是在我那
Yes,the artifact is with me now.
你当然能先看一下 但是没多少时间喔
Of course you can see it but time is of the essence.
我在等一些意大利石雕板
I'm expecting a consignment of Italian lithographs...
都装在些不同的箱子里面 当然都没记号的了
all arriving this afternoon in identical boxes,unmarked of course.
Emmerick的电话 Jensen先生 我马上给你转接
Mr.Emmerick's phone.Mr.Jensen,I'll put you right through.
Hyotona先生,你能先等一下吗 马德里那边的客户给我来电话了
Yes,Mr.Hyotona,I'll have to place you on hold.It's my Madrid dealer.
Jensen先生
Mr.Jensen.
还有另外一个拍卖会 我想你会感兴趣的
I'm afraid there's another interested party.
公元600年摩西五经的原版手抄本
Well,an original,illuminated,6th century transcript...
这可是难得的机会啊 肯定要引起轰动的
of the Pentateuchal books of the Bible is bound to generate a lot of buzz.
你见过那手抄本吗
You've seen the Photostats?
其中有几页连原版福音书也没办法比的
Some of these pictures put even the Book of Kells to shame.
什么 你没见过?
What's that?You haven't seen them?
我助手 Jackson博士没跟你在一起吗?
My associate,Professor Jackson,isn't with you?
他妈的Jackson博士在哪?
Ash,where is Professor sodding Jackson?
Albert 不见人了 我找不到他
Albert hasn't shown.I can't raise him.
我想他没去找你肯定是有原因的
I'm sure there's a very good reason why he's not with you.
Albert没出现
Albert's not turned up.
等一下Jensen先生 我的助理刚进来
One moment please,Mr.Jensen,my PA has just walked in.
Albert没出现?什么意思?
What do you mean he's not turned up?
就是他没去罗
He ain't there,okay?
他不见踪影 怎么也找不到他
He's a no- show,Mickey.The street is an Albert- free zone.
本作品由Norm HALFCD Team倾情奉献\N感谢原作提供资源.仅供学习交流.严禁用于商业行为\N请自觉于下载后24小时内删除!如果喜欢本片,请购买正版!
更多精彩 尽在www.NormTeam.com
压制:鬼谷子 字幕:鬼谷子\NCompression:GV-Sir Subtitles:GV-Sir
捐献点吧?
For the poor?
你没事吧
Are you troubled,my son?
我想我今天看到了未来
I think I saw the future today.
上帝有时是会指引我们 让我们看到我们要走的路
God sometimes gives us glimpses of the path we are traveling.
我以前总以为我知道自己要干什么
I always thought I knew just where I was headed.
事实上
Truth is,Sister...
但我其实是不清楚的
now I'm not so sure.
别灰心
Do not despair.
希望在明天嘛
There is always hope.
我不是灰心 我只是不大相信希望这玩意
I don't mean to split hairs,Sister,but I don't believe in hope exactly.
我相信的是机会
I prefer to call it chance.
应该抓紧的机会
And a chance has to be grabbed.
你有什么事
What's your problem,my son?
我不是虔诚的基督徒
I'm not a churchgoer,Father.
但我妻子是
The wife's a big fan,though.
她让我来一下
She told me to light a candle to Saint Marie of the Incarnation.
只要你能帮我 不管什么神佛我都相信
I'll bend the knee to any statue you like.But you have got to help me.
飞天大盗 第2季第2集
S02E02 Confessions
Albie.我们很担心你呢
Albie.We were worried.
你是我护士啊 这么紧张?我没事啊
What are you,my nurse?I'm fine.
有个好消息跟一个坏消息
Look,there's bad news and there's good news.
你没去那 我们丢了那笔生意
When you didn't show,the marks lost their bottle.
那坏消息你们知道了
So you've had the bad,then.
- 你去哪了 - 我们真的很担心你啊
- Where the hell were you? - We were worried.
Albie,你要放我们鸽子 也不要在这个时候啊
Albie,if you want to go off-piste,at least let the rest of us know.
我也不想那样的
This one has always been a no-no.
我也觉得很对不起你们
I've had a bad feeling from the off.
好了好了 那好消息是什么
Okay,so what's the good news?
Keyes.我认识他
Johnny Keyes.Keyes.Oh,yeah.I know him.
出生贫民区 是个心狠手辣的人喔
Proper hard man.Proper East End,he is.
我还以为他只是个厨师
I thought he was a chef.
'"厨房皇帝'" 我老婆有那本书
'"The Kitchen King.'" Yeah,my missus had that book.
那就是说你在教堂见到一个很会炒菜的厨子罗
So you saw a fancy chef in a church.
不会这么无聊吧
Whoopee diddley doo!
不是厨师 我见到的是一个有权有势的人
No.I saw a powerful,arrogant thug.
他有钱得要命 可又烦得要死
With cash in his pockets and desperation in his eyes.
他烦什么?
What's he got to be desperate about?
他出生贫民窟 打家劫舍 白手兴家
He grew up on the streets,robbing houses,talking with his fists.
对了 还抢过银行
Yeah,not to mention turning over a couple of banks.
不是一两次喔 是很多次啊
And he did time for that.A lot of time.
有人说他就该判终身监禁
Some say they should have thrown away the key.
那人骨子里就是个恶魔
This man was evil personified.
我在监狱里也是跟他们一样
Inside I was just like the rest of them.A nobody.
无聊时还不时帮帮厨子打杂
I did kitchen detail just to pass the time at first.
后来却真的成了兴趣
But then it got into my blood.
我拼命的学习厨艺
And I was devouring books.Hungry to learn.
开始有了些名气
Cooking for the big men.
他出狱后买下一家餐馆
So he gets out of prison and buys a restaurant with a bag of gold bullion.
- 现在就经营着K's - K's.
- And now of course,he runs K's. - K's.
那里现在要订个位子难死了
Who do you have to kill to get a table in there these days?
他说是怕我被人杀了
He said it's in case I get a puncture.
那他还烦什么
So why is he desperate?
很多人都忘了他还有个孩子
What most people have forgotten is the story of James.
叫James的
His son.
1974年,他那一岁的孩子被绑架
In 1974,his one- year-old son was kidnapped.
之后就再也没有音信了
Never to be heard or seen again.
我当时树敌很多
I had a lot of enemies in those days.
我也不知道是谁带走了他
But I'll never know which bastard took him.
我付不起赎金 我哪有那么多钱
I couldn't pay what they wanted.I didn't have the ransom,all right?
我得找他
I've got to find him.
希望还来得及
Before it's too late.
那个Keyes得病了
Keyes is sick.
心脏病 说不定哪天自己就挂掉了 当然想找回个继承人
A bum ticker.He wants to find his heir before they stick him in the ground.
James现在该32岁了
James would be 32 now.
你想找人冒充他儿子
So you're talking birthrights...
你就是想这么做吧
inheritance,that's your angle,is it?
不好意思打断一下 不过做他孩子还真是可怜
Sorry,but stinging some guy who's still grieving over his long lost son?
别同情他
Don't shed one tear for him,my dear.
那人本身就害人不浅了
The guy's a nasty piece of work.
我觉得他就在我附近
I got a feeling in my bones that he's close.
我会给钱他
I got money for him.
让他搞搞生意什么的
Plenty to help him make something of himself,the way I did.
如果用钱能补偿他
If I could give him the money...
我就给他钱
least then I'd feel I'd done something for him.
那又怎样呢
Now what?
我想让他跟他孩子"团聚"
I think we should reunite him with his long lost son.
Albert.
你今天去教堂干吗?
What the hell were you doing in a church today?
今天下午Gil Stewart死了
Gil Stewart died this afternoon.
我一直陪着他
I was there at the end.
不是吧 死了?你跟他好得就像两兄弟
Oh,God.I'm so sorry,Albert.You two were like brothers.
我们在拉斯维加斯就开始合作
We worked Vegas together.
他人好聪明的
That man was made for bright lights.
可惜啊
Poor bastard.
他在牙科医院 中风死了
Died of a stroke in a dental surgery.
我们该起诉那医生
Well,someone should sue them.
他就是那冒牌医生
He was pretending to be the dentist.
他死前
Before he died...
把这交给我
he gave me this.
他的结婚戒指
His wedding ring.
做了这么多年骗子
All those years of hard grift...
他死的时候却拿着个电动牙刷
and he dies holding a bottle of plaque remover.
我要是死了
When I die,Mickey...
你得往我口袋塞满钱
I want my pockets to be filled with cash.
把Keyes的钱骗到手吧 Michael
Let's take Keyes' money,Michael.
那么
So.
给他弄个败家子 你看怎样
How do you feel about playing the prodigal son then?
好吧?
Well?
Stacie 起起Keyes的老底.
Stacie,find out as much as possible about Keyes'past.
越了解他才越能使他相信Danny是他儿子
The details will help convince him that Danny is his son.
这些旧新闻是说有个凶悍的匪徒
These old articles talk about a vicious armed robber...
勒索 抢劫 无恶不作
into everything from extortion to protection rackets.
但他一出狱 洗手不干了
But once Keyes gets out of jail,he reinvents himself.
一转眼就成了个厨师
Suddenly he's about as dangerous as Delia Smith.
我想谁也有些事不见得人的
Well,I reckon she's got a dark side.
来点三文鱼?
Salmon nibble?
有人说他骗了他老朋友的钱
One theory is that he swindled some of his old compadres out of money.
所以那次绑架应该是仇家报复
The kidnap was revenge.
好的 那有什么特别
Okay.So how do we usually get a mark?
他们都吝啬的狠
We appeal to their greed.
那家伙特意不给赎金的 对吧
This bloke's not looking to make money,is he?
他就那样让孩子给人带走算了
He's looking to give it away.
我们这次玩玩亲情戏罗
So we spin him a sob story.
那够了吗?
Will that be enough?
咱们要使他心甘情愿给我们送钱啊
You see giving Danny the money has to be his idea.
你那是什么
What you got in there?
中午吃的肉 看看
Got luncheon meat.Obviously.
- 都快坏掉了 - 对啊 我就爱这样的味道
- That's on the turn. - Yeah,that's how I like it.
跟Albert一起的是谁?
Who's Albert with?
- 他的新朋友 - 是吗
- His new best friends. - Oh,yeah.
是今天早上他碰到的一些的士司机
Yeah,bunch of cab drivers he met this morning.
三个Q
Three jacks.
- 好大的牌喔 - 对啊 是很大
- Happens to the best of them. - Yeah.It does.
四个皇
Four kings.
你输了 老人家
You lose,old-timer.
- 再来吗? - 今天不了
- Go again? - Soon.I hope.
他赌了好几把了吧
So,he's had a few,then?
对啊 来好久了
Yeah.He's been here a while.
虎落平原被犬欺啊
A rose in a bed of thorns.
还没干完这事之前不要再赌了
We keep away from blokes on a hot streak unless we got another deck up our sleeve.
Albert?
听着 兄弟 你再怎么赌Gil也不会死而复生
Look,mate,gambling's not going to bring Gil back.
你打电话给Keyes没?
Have you called Keyes yet?
没有 我不想预约 我得跟Keyes谈谈
No,I don't wish to make a reservation.I wish to speak to Mr.Keyes.
我是O'Brien神父
Yeah,Father O'Brien.
当然不会有像红酒那样香醇的东西
Of course there's nothing like a wine tasting en primeur.
我刚从Burgundy回来
I've just come back from a chateau in Burgundy.
那真是高级享受
Top stuff.
不行
No.
当然 这是很浪费的
Of course,it's all bloody show.Still.
但我可是嗜酒如命啊
I'm a sucker for the grape.
你刚才说你是谁?
Who'd you say you were again?
Chris.
Family Ties是我开的 我们帮人去找回失散得亲人
I run Family Ties.We help reunite estranged families.
我一点都不懂得品酒
I don't know anything about wine.
这国家只有200人懂得品酒
Only about 200 people in this country do.
Sammy厉害得一个顶他们三个
Sammy here accounts for about three of them.
是神父叫你来的
So the priest sent you,then?
他三年前就给我们打过电话
He called us about three years ago.
他当时想找自己的家人
Trying to locate his real family.
我现在想说是你的儿子 James
I'm talking about James.Your son.
我知道很难要你相信 但请听我说
I know this is difficult,but please believe me when I say...
不可能
There's no way.
神父就打了一个电话 就找到我儿子了?这么简单?
The priest makes one call and finds my son just like that?
好吧
All right.
你准备好了就给我电话吧
Call us when you're ready.
你好 是求职中介吗?
Hello,is that Jobseekers?
我想找一批人
Yes,I'm wondering if you could help me.I'm looking for some enthusiastic...
要懂得电话礼仪的 要很有热情的
candidates with a very good telephone manner.
James三岁开始就开始被不同的人领养
James has been in and out of foster homes since he was three.
还被贩卖给一对不能生育的夫妇
He was illegally sold to a childless couple...
但是他们后来又改变主意 违弃了他
who had a change of heart and abandoned him.
当时应该会有人发现他是你儿子的 但很可惜 没有
He should have been identified as your son,but unfortunately he wasn't.
我不相信你们找到他了
I don't buy that you've found him.
是他找到 Keyes先生
He found you,Mr.Keyes.
很久前的事了
Quite some time ago.
要不是O'Brien神父给我们电话
He didn't know if you'd want to see him.But when Father O'Brien called us...
他才不知道你会不会认他呢
that's when James knew.
我会联系你的
I'll be in touch.
我希望这场现场演练能
I hope this brief role-play has given you some idea...
让你体会到你将来的工作环境
of the environment you'd be expected to work in.
Starkey先生会给你们发一些面试题目 你们完成它 交好 就可以离开
Mr.Starkey will hand out questionnaires.Please hand them back as you leave.
我们会在你们之中挑选两位 一有消息我们就会通知你们
And we'll be in touch with the lucky two we've chosen in due course.
非常感谢你们到来
Thank you for your time.
那是什么?
What is that?
不要打开橱柜看喔
Don't look in the cupboard.
它不会跳出来吓我一跳吧
Is it gonna jump out?
- 上帝啊 - 都告诉你不要了
- Jesus! - I warned you.
不然你以为放个空气清新机在这干吗
What do you think the air freshener's are for?
Albie.
葬礼我们就不要去了
Nobody's going to the funeral.
但是Gil会喜欢这的
But,Gil would have loved this.
他墓碑上名字写的是Benedict Doonan.
He's being buried under the name of Benedict Doonan.
死的时候是冒牌牙医 所以只能用那名
Died a dentist.Buried a dentist.
他的墓碑上还不能写自己的名字?
So he doesn't get his own name on his headstone?
- 不是吧 - 有什么关系
- Bummer. - What does it matter?
会有谁会悼念他?
Who's gonna be there to cry for him?
干吗发那么大火
What's eating Gilbert Grape?
他不会承认 但是他的确很难过的
Well,he won't admit it,but it's grief.
你好,这是Chris
Hello,Chris speaking.
好的 完全没问题 我们会安排的
Yeah,no that's no trouble at all.We can get that arranged.Yeah.
好的 再见
Okay,cheers.
是Keyes的律师
That was Keyes' lawyer.
他们想要做DNA测试
They want a blood test.
快件 医用肝 要送去几楼
Organ courier.Theater.Which floor?
你送货清单呢?
Your contact is?
清单落在车上了
Contact sheet's back in my panniers.
没听说有人要进行移植手术啊
I wasn't told of a transplant.
好的 对不起 如果你不要动手术
Yeah,well sorry,love,but seeing as you're not doing the operation...
那是不是他们也不要呢?
maybe they didn't make you a priority.Which floor?
- 恐怕我还是不能让你进去 - 好的
- I'm afraid I can't let you through until... - Right.Okay.
楼上有个病号 他脸色疮白 就等着这东西
There's a fella upstairs the same color as a canary and he's waiting for one of these.
一开始手术 机器一开 就帮他换好肝了
On a slab.On a drip.Cut open.With a little machine doing the job of his liver for him.
那你要让他再等我去拿我的清单吗
You want to ask him if he minds hanging on a bit while I go and get my clipboard?
谢谢
Thank you.
刚好你来了
Staff.Excellent.
我需要在半小时后做血液化验 给我准备一下
I'll need someone available to take a blood sample for me in about half an hour.
可以的话
Get me three chairs and an internal phone...
还要三张椅子和内线电话 一杯咖啡 放三颗糖
and coffee,three sugars if you can.
我是医生
The doctor...
刚上任的
is in.
找Dr.Reef的吧 对 他通知过我们了
Dr.Reef.Yes,he phoned to let us know.
- 在第一楼上去 跟着指示牌走就到了 - 好的
- First floor and follow the signs. - Cheers.
这很不正常
This is all rather unorthodox.
应该是给你们寄结果的
Protocol is to send these results in the post.
但既然你坚持要现在就知道结果
But since you insist on knowing now.
那就让我看看
Let's have it.
我们将你的DNA样本跟James Haworth的对比过
We compared the DNA from your sample to that of James Haworth.
结果表明相似度达到99.99%.
The relative chance of paternity is 99.99%.
那James....
So James....
应该可以确认了
It is as beyond doubt as it can be.
是你亲生的Keyes先生
He is your son,Mr.Keyes.
我要再找人确认一下
I want a second opinion.
什么
I'm sorry?
我要有人来再确认一下
I want it reconfirmed.Now.
- 你可以看这报告 - 我就要这样做
- Well,you can see the results. - It's the way I do things.
你去找另外一位医生来
You get another doctor in.Now.
我不知道能不能麻烦其他医生 大家都很忙的
Well,I'm not sure I can just pull a colleague off the corridor.
如果这样做才能让Keyes放心 那你就这样做好了
If it'll put Mr.Keyes' mind at rest,Doctor.
好的
Very well.
你要喝点什么吗
Do you want a cup of something?
好久了 他搞什么啊 有点不对劲
He's been ages.He's made a cock-up.I knew this wasn't right.
对 我想也是
Yeah,think I agree.
那 我们就走了?
What,we're going?
我们呆在这也没办法啊
Well,it's not doing you any good pacing up and down here.
再说 他们寄给你鉴定报告上就会有再次认可的
Besides,they can always send the second opinion in the post.
- 你觉得我们真该就这样走了? - 你决定好了 这是你的问题
- Do you really think we should go? - It's your call.You're in the driving seat.
我是帮人家团聚不是拆散人家的
I'm here to unite people not alienate them.
再等5分钟好了
Five more minutes.
好的
Okay.
这是Mansfield医生
This is Dr.Mansfield.
Mansfield我给你看看这化验报告
Dr.Mansfield,I will show you these two DNA results.
你来看一下
Your assessment,please.
99.99% 相似
99.99% match,Doctor.
- 那他们有血缘关系罗 - 对的
- They're related? - Yes.
我口好干
I need a drink.
做的好
You did very well.
- 那我现在算是个医生罗 - 当然
- So am I a doctor now? - Definitely.
那我能帮人动手术吗 我想帮人开刀 做心脏手术 眼部手术 肺部手术
Do I get to do operations?I'd like to operate on a heart,or an eye,or a lung.
站稳 站稳啊 吃了那些药是会让人走路都走不稳的
Steady,these pre-meds can really give you the wobbles.
还有脑部手术
Or a brain.
我带你回你病床好了
Yeah,let's get you back to bed.
我是帮你们而已
God,the things I do for you guys.
- 你漂亮极了 - 对 好看极了
- You look cute. - Yeah,you look fantastic.
他的老婆叫Juliette Keyes.Keyes是她第三任丈夫了
Juliette Keyes.She's on to her third husband.
她肯定想要知道你是不是为了钱来的
She'll want to know what you're after financially.
那肯定罗 但是不是已经验过DNA了吗?她该相信了吧
Yeah,but the blood test confirms it,doesn't it?I'm his son.
不知道 我还是得过来 以防特殊情况
But still,I'll be there to stage-manage.
- 你挺漂亮的喔 我们吃顿饭吧 - 开开玩笑而已啊
- Okay,you look great,let's go eat. - Just looking.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的 来
It's okay,come on.
好的
Right.
这是James
This is James.
Jimmy 人人都叫我Jimmy
Jimmy.Everyone calls me Jimmy.
这是Jimmy的未婚妻Paula
And this is Jimmy's missus-to-be,Paula.
这地方好漂亮 是吧 Jimmy?
This is an amazing place.Isn't it amazing,Jimmy?
是的 很漂亮
Yeah.It's amazing.
我叫Juliette.
I'm Juliette.
他这么帅啊 Johnny你说是吧
Handsome devil isn't he,Johnny.
是你找上我们的 是吧
So you found us all right,then?
对啊
Yeah.
花了好几年时间了
Well,it took a few years.
最主要的是
The important thing...
一开始 不要有什么顾虑 怀疑 什么的
at this very early stage is not to worry about any doubts or fears or anything.
大家都要耐心点
Just,you know,be patient.
这地方装修不错啊
It's an amazing place,this.
你想在饮食行业立足 就得花点心思
You got to keep ahead in the restaurant game.
客人来吃顿饭 你们厨师就得争的头破血流
Customers will eat the food,but when it comes to other chefs,it's dog eat dog.
这装修花了我们不少钱啊
Cost us everything,this place.
真厉害
It's amazing.
写菜谱有个窍门 就是要简洁一点
Keep the menus brief,that's the trick.
客人都是想人家来告诉他该吃什么的
People want to be told what to eat.
你最拿手做什么菜
So what are you cooking,Jimmy?
我现在还刚开始
Well,I'm just at Burger Chef right now.
我也有些拿手菜
But I've done stints in some fancy places,ain't I?
- 对 - 羊肉 跟苹果塔
- Yeah. - Lamb and apple tatties.
我也会做 我做的口味很重的
That's one of mine,with a spicy fig sauce.
加点伴菜 烤一下
Saffron,roasties.
不要太花俏
You don't want to get too fancy.
如果酱料做的好
Simple food tells its own story...
简简单单也会很好吃
providing it's sauced right.Here.
试试味
Try that.
别装了 我知道你在想什么 Jimmy
Don't dawdle,know your mind,Jimmy.
你想吓走我的客人啊?
Are you taking the piss out of me with this chowder?
你往汤里放什么了?
On second thoughts,have you put the piss in the chowder?
那
So.
你很喜欢做菜 Jimmy
You're mad about your food,Jimmy.
那你手艺行吗?
But have you got what it takes?
没位置了 对不起 先生 但我
No,I am dreadfully sorry,sir.Yeah,but I...
先生 你这样说也没用
Sir,shouting at the maitre d' doesn't alter the fact that there is...
预定星期天中午的桌子要等四个礼拜 再见
a four-week waiting list for Sunday lunch.Goodbye.
对有些人就该这样
Some people.
- 哇 四星期? - 要订星期六晚上的桌子要等8星期呢
- Wow,four weeks? - Eight weeks for a Saturday night.
我们还有一些桌子预留给 一些名人 他们总会很晚才来订位
We always keep a couple of tables on stand-by for those last minute celebs.
你无聊时干什么?
What you doing out here on your Ionesome?
我不无聊 我开了两个公司 还有经营一个社会团体
Two's company,a social worker's a crowd.
我们没被人耍吧 Chris?
We're not being wound up,are we,Chris?
他不是为钱而来的 对吧?以前也有人这样做过
He isn't a gold-digger,is he?Because we've had someone try it on before.
- 不 Jimmy是真的 - 是就最好
- No,Jimmy's for real. - Well,he'd better be.
或者他是有心要骗Johnny的 他所说得又一点不差
Or knowing Johnny,God help him.
你要自己打拼事业 很好
Makes no odds how much you pay for your Chateaubriand...
是金子总要发光的
the bins still stink.
我也希望
Yeah,I suppose so.
这地方我打算用来做个酒窖 在这玻璃幕墙后面
I'm going to put a visible wine cellar out here,behind a glass partition.
很好的一个酒窖
Beautiful thing,a good cellar.
听起来不错
Sounds fantastic...
Keyes.
Mr.Keyes.
叫我Johnny好了
Call me Johnny,at least.
那
So.
你想开一家酒吧
You want to open a gastro-pub.
是有这么打算过
Well,that's the plan.
不过 现在说还早呢
I mean,that's a long way off.
妈死的时候痛苦吗?
So did Mom suffer much before she died?
你妈?
Your mom?
不 她死的很安详 死于炎症
No.It was quick.The cancer was all through her.
我们当时已经分开了 我家人不让我去见她
We were separated by then.The family didn't let me go to the hospital.
我只去了葬礼
Just the funeral.Bastards.
当时我没发火 我没哭
I wasn't angry.I didn't cry.
当你白手兴家的时候 你就学会了尊严 而不是示弱
When you come from nowhere you learn pride.No weakness,yeah?
好了
Look.
明晚 再到这 吃顿饭
Tomorrow night.In here.A family party.
来不来 怎么了
Come on,yes or no.What's the matter?
好的 来 明晚
Yeah,all right,then.Yeah,tomorrow.
我告诉你 他要是愿意 他会把全盘生意都让我接手
I tell you now,if he could,he'd hand me the whole business on a plate today.
- 我不信 - 你说什么啊
- I don't think so. - What are you talking about?
你们是有血缘关系 但还没到那分上 你得再努力一下 Danny
There's a connection but there's no bond.You need to bond,Danny.
什么?
What?
你不如去吻他一下吧
Why don't you give him a kiss?
好的
Oh,yes.
这放好久了
Eddie's aunt's attic.
Everton赢了FA锦标赛之后就没动过
Hasn't been cleaned since Everton won the FA Cup.
看这蜘蛛网 粘呼呼的
Killer cobwebs.Sticky,with those little bits of grit.
好极了
It's very nice,yeah.
我们要帮帮Danny
We need to beef Danny up.
明晚在K's订一桌
Book a table at K's for tomorrow night.
要等8星期耶
Eight-week waiting list.
有问题啊?
Problem?
没有
Nope.
各位
Hey,guys.
大家都想
Guys,you wouldn't be interested in having your picture snapped...
跟Justin Timberlake来张合照吧
with Justin Timberlake,would you?
我听说他在K's吃饭
Yeah,I got the nod he's eating at K's,and the pics always look better...
人多一点才热闹的 去吧
with a little bit of a crowd,you know?Go on.Off you go.
快去 我们爱Justin!快去
Go on quickly.We love Justin!Off you go.Come on.
就在街角那边 快
Just around the corner.Go quickly.
快去
Will you please leave right now!
我不想
I don't want to have....
听我说 我不想报警 快走
Listen to me,I don't want to call the police.Now go!
对不起
Excuse me.
我订桌子的时候不是说了要保密的吗?
When I book a table I ask for discretion to the max.
你以为Timberlake想人知道他要到西区来吃饭啊?
Why do you think Mr.Timberlake is choosing to dine out of the West End?
- 我搞不懂 - 是Justin Timberlake 你这笨蛋
- I don't understand. - Justin Timberlake,you moron.
他没订桌子啊 我可以跟老板娘确认一下
He's not in the book.I can check with Ms.Keyes.
Justin当然没订 他叫人帮他订的
No,Justin doesn't do books.He comes in under the wire.
反正不是叫我订的
Not under my wire,sir.
我告诉你怎么办吧 别准备那桌子
I'll tell you what we'll do,then.Don't get the table ready.
我们就在这等他来
Instead we'll wait in the foyer here with the adoring hordes...
到时你就可以跟他解释了
so you can explain it all to Justin and his people when he arrives.
到时就更不好办了吧
Just doesn't look good for a place like this,does it?
我可以说这跟我们没关系
Well,I can assure you,sir,this publicity leak had nothing to do with us.
到时粉丝都来了 你能怎么办
The hard-core ones pick it up off the fan sites.What can you do?
我会叫Justin的司机晚一个小时到
I'll take the table and tell Justin's driver to delay for an hour.
Justin会谅解的 他是个明白人
Justin's a regular guy.He'll understand.
去准备桌子吧 不要靠窗的 弄得低调一点
Nothing by a window,no place settings facing west.Lead on.
他是谁 怎么占着张四人桌子
Who is he and why has he got a table for four on his own?
好的 好好招待他
All right.Look after him.
但是通知厨房把他名字记在黑名单上
But tell the kitchens to check his face against the wanted list.
- 什么是 黑名单 - 我们厨房有张清单
- What's a "wanted list"? - We have photos in the kitchen...
用来记着评论家跟检查员的名字
so the staff can spot the restaurant critics and the Michelin inspectors.
那他们就会好好照顾那些人了
It helps the monkeys know who the hunters are.
干吗还还不动手你的事业 Jimmy
So why waste your life frying burgers,Jimmy?
还不是时候啊
Well,it's regular bunce,isn't it?You know.
我们得先结婚了再说
We got a wedding to think about,haven't we.
不是吧 你的尊严咧?
Sod that.What about your pride?
这么多水就那么一点柠檬 还有 你的黄油不能软一点吗?
Sparkling water with a twist of lime,and can you get this butter softened?
硬的要命
It's like a slab of ice.
你打算往哪集资去开酒吧
So where you gonna get the money for this gastro-pub?
阿
Well...
- 银行看过我们的信用额后 - 银行?
- once the banks know they can trust us... - Banks?
他们借了不好还喔
Crooks with pens in their pockets.Trust me,I know.
要不然我们去哪弄那钱
Well,how else are we gonna get the capital?
- 你不能跟银行搞上 - 服务生
- You can't let them run you. - Waiter.
这豆子里面都是水 还有
The split-pea soup's watery and the Neuf- du- Pape...
这酒比室温高了至少两度
at least two degrees above ambient temperature.
你懂不懂啊
Do you have any idea....
算了 把我的烤羊肉拿上来
Forget it,just bring my lamb casserole.
别跟我说 你昨天之后就没了劲了
Don't tell me you've lost your nerve after yesterday.
你们两个怎么认识的
So how'd you two meet?
- 我们就在酒吧碰上的 - 好奇怪他会这么做
- We just got chatting in a bar. - Surprised he had the nerve.
- 什么意思 - 他很有冲劲 但是他很害羞的
- Well,how'd you mean? - He's a cracking boy,but he's shy.
他不像会去泡mm的
Some people ain't suited for the cut and thrust.
你 过来 这羊肉吃起来就像狗肉
You!Here.Now.This lamb tastes like boiled dog.
拿走
Get rid of it.
我是Johnny Keyes 有什么问题
Johnny Keyes.There's a problem?
你是生出来就不会做菜
My God,were you born with such perception or did you learn it from...
－还是你还根本没学好?－你如果有什么不满
- some ancient Chinese master? - lf you're dissatisfied...
我可是娱乐界的名人 我认识好多评论家
I'm a major player in the entertainment world and I know a lot of critics.
- 我过去一下 - 我给他们说一声 那你这地方就
- Excuse me. - One word from me and this place...
等一下 Jimmy 不要
Wait.No,Jimmy,don't.
就被人家评论的一文不值
...will be on the receiving end of a review with three of my favorite words:
'令人作呕的食品"令人厌恶的服务态度"一切都令人不快'
"nauseating," "heinous," and "putrid."
你如果不住嘴的话 你可要吃不了兜着走
If you don't shut up,it's not the food that you're gonna be complaining about.
你这小子敢这样对我?
Call off the whelp.
你不想活了?
Unless you want this dump black-listed by the likes of Beyonce.
Johnny Keyes付出努力才建起这家餐馆
Johnny Keyes built this place up from nothing.
而像你这样的人就只会贬低人家
People like you only have a talent for pissing on other people's hard work.
那你去啊 你告诉你的评论家朋友 去叫他们写你的评论啊
Well go on,mate.Go and get your friend,go and write your review.
好!是那样的话 你就等着收我律师写的信吧!
All right?And then wait to see the letter that lands on your doorstep...
上面会写
which will have my three favorite words:
"诽谤者"""人云亦云"
"libelous," "unsubstantiated"...
"法庭上见"
and "court-case."
法庭上见 我才不怕呢
"Court case" is two words.
好啊 那就走着瞧
Yeah,well I used a bloody hyphen!
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are.
但你犯大错了
But you just made a big mistake.
没有 他没有 我也会这样说的
No,he didn't.Now make like one.
我告诉你他是谁 他是我的儿子 我失散多年的儿子
And I'll tell you who he is.He's my son.My long lost son.
干杯吧 各位
Champagne for everyone!
我儿子回来了
My son is home.Yes.
开牌见我 老人家
Monkey to see me,old-timer.
你赢光我的钱了
You have cleaned me out.
这
Here.
这是真银的
It's real silver.
来 Jimmy 我们喝一杯
Come on,Jimmy.Let's get a drink.
他想我们今晚在这过夜
He wants us to stay the night.
那怎样?
So?
我要睡哪?
Where am I gonna sleep?
你以为你是佣人啊?
Who'd you think you are,Sister Wendy?
你当然要跟我一起睡喔
You're gonna be sleeping with me,sweetie.
好的
Fine.
记得不要乱来
So long as you remember there's a no-fly zone.
他做什么都要顺着他
Laugh at his jokes.Drink his drinks.
多说些好听的讨好他 知道不?
Just to keep being a chip off the old block for Keyes.Okay?
好了 Chris
Come on,Chris,mate.
什么事
What's going on?
没 他说我们该走了
Well,he's saying he thinks that we should go.
我觉得这太快了
I just think it's too much,too soon.
怎么太快了 我们可是失散了32年啊
How can it be too much?I've missed out on the last 32 years.
今晚就在这过了
Stay.
谁先抽到皇的
First one to get the picture card...
今晚就睡床
gets the bed.
你没事吧?
You all right?
没
Yeah.
St.Balthazar.
是玩牌人的守护神
Patron saint of card players.
我是不是该再做些什么讨好他呢
I should've lit a candle to him before I took on that cabbie again.
那神是个金矿 那你醒目一点 讨好讨好他
The bloke's on hot streak.I told you,stay away or load the deck.
我知道了
Yeah.
你说 Danny 那冒牌儿子做的怎样?
Tell me,is Danny making a good son?
应该很好
Yeah,perfect son.
你有想过生个孩子吗?
Do you ever wish that you had kids,Ash?
我们这种人肯定要生孩子的
Well,it's the life we sign up for,isn't it?
你呢
What about you?
Mickey跟Danny说话的样子和我以前跟Mickey说话的样子一样
The way Mickey talks to Danny reminds me of the way I used to talk to Mickey.
我知道
Yeah,I know.
当你再没什么可以教后辈了
You know there's a horrible point in your life when you realize...
只有自己去犯一些错
that you've got nothing to teach the younger ones...
让他们从中学习
except through your mistakes.
- 我死了之后 - 别说这些
- But when I die... - No,don't start.
听我说 我死了之后 我要死得富贵
No,when I die,I'm gonna die rich.
我不要人为我歌功颂德
And I don't want any eulogies...
也不要人为我伤心
or tears.
我只想听人家说 "这里葬的是Albert Stroller
I just want people to say,"There lies Albert Stroller.
他钱多到都带不下去
"He couldn't take it with him.
但是他
"But by thunder...
毕竟曾经辉煌过
"at least he has it all on him."
不论什么 你都能从人家手上骗到手
You can cheat anyone out of anything.
我想连死神你都能骗的 到时你就长命百岁了
I think you'll cheat Death and live forever.
别油嘴滑舌的了
Don't be flippant.
我到死那天都会拼命赚钱的
I'll still be chasing the cons when I fall off my perch.
你赌的太多了
You're gambling too much.
- 别再这样了 - 别说了 让我静一下
- Don't do it to yourself,mate. - Shut up and leave me alone.
Gil是你的好朋友 你当然忘不了他
Gil was your friend and you miss him,I know...
我说让我静一下
I said leave me alone!
可能Keyes...
That's probably Keyes...
在想着
thinking about us...
以为我们在干那事
doing it.
我们不该让他失望喔 对吧
We shouldn't disappoint him then,should we?
他儿子我可是个贫民区出生的小淫虫啊
I mean I am supposed to be a chip off the old block.
Danny.
不 我觉得这主意不错
Yeah,I'm thinking that's a very good point.
- 我要来了 - 不要
- I gotta close the deal. - No.
我要来一下
Yeah,I'm gonna close the deal.
Paula 你还要吗
Paula,do you think we should?
你还不够啊
Okay,then,you're insatiable,ain't you?
我就喜欢你这样叫
I love it when you make those noises.
晚安
Night,then.
Good night.
我想给些钱你们做生意
I want to give you two some money.
这人在试我们啊?
Mr.Bombastic has done it again.
Danny.
我如果现在能跟你谈谈
If I could speak to you right now across this table...
- 你会教我怎么做呢? - 听我说
- what would I advise you to do? - Give it a break.
别再跟他玩了
Can we stop playing Jedi master for two minutes?
既然他给钱 我要算了
Okay,it's working just dandy andy pandy.He's offering.I should accept.
那她呢?她会怎么想
And what about her?
你要了就惨了
You never wanted his charity,Danny.
因为他知道你是有尊严的 钱你要自己挣回来
No,because you have your pride.You want to make it on your own.
所以你不要要他的钱
And that's why you're going to turn his offer down.
- 我们说好的 Danny. - 那 好吧
- Just like we agreed,Danny. - All right,then.
你为什么不问
Now why don't you ask me...
昨晚的事?
what you're gagging to ask me?
没必要啊 你们昨晚肯定什么都没干
No,I don't have to.I know you two were faking last night.
为什么
Why?
想想就知道了
It's a common mistake.
你们谁都不会有那心情的
But no one has that good a time of it.
我当时做错了决定 就失去了你 我很懊悔
I made a judgment call,and I lost you.It haunts me,Jimmy.
我现在给你点钱 都你捏补不了32年来带给你的伤害
I can't make up for the last 32 years but I can help you now.
我把这钱投资在你身上
I want to invest in your future.
亲爱的 我们晚点再谈这 好吗
Darling,don't you think we should talk about this later?
但是我想自己白手兴家
You know I want to make it on my own.
对 Jimmy说的对 我们想自己打拼自己的事业
Yeah,Jimmy's right.We want to carve a life on our own terms.Our way.
那么
What about this,then?
我今晚去你家 尝尝你手艺
I come over to your place and you cook me your piece de resistance.
我的手艺?
Cook for you?
如果你手艺好的话 我就给你钱 作为投资
And if your foods good enough,then I'll invest.
- 你也来吧 - 我约了人
- You'll come won't you,sweetheart? - I've got a pedicure.
我可是很难侍侯的喔
And I'll be tough on you.
你也是知道的
'Cause I know that's what you want.
看 他也想这样
Look at that face.He loves the idea.
明晚5点 我就过去你那
Tomorrow at 5:00.Your place.
我家?
My place?
好的 5点去我家
Great,yeah,my place.
这里光线很好 但你们的人可能会用自己的设备来拍
There's a lot of light.But I expect you guys provide your own.
那电影叫什么?
What's it called again?
Zombie Towers.
讲的是在公寓里面 其实隐藏着通向地狱的门
Block of flats.That's the gateway to Hell.
这地方连拍摄用的手推车都放不进来
Now I don't think there's enough room to run a dolly in here.
我只能用在外面用吊车
Hell,I may just have to ride that bad boy on the crane.
把镜头从外面伸进来
Come up here through the window.Boom.
好了Eaves我们片子的预算很紧
Now Mr.Eaves,we're wrestling a very tight budget.
租一个月也就花你2000
One month's lease is still going to cost you two grand.
我跟你算算帐
Let me crunch you some figures.
就是非林就22万了
The net cost of the picture is 2.2 mil.
美国电影要打入北美市场还要另外给30万
U.S.studio will pick up North American rights for 3 mil.
还有国内跟欧洲市场的宣传费
A consortium will handle domestic and European...
还要付DVD跟有线电视商的钱
and a third party's gonna take care of DVD and cable.
电影还没上画就得付50多万
So we're looking to clear about 5 mil before box office.
你真以为我们开银行啊?
So you would think that we have money to burn.But,alas,no.
当然 如果票房收的好的话又另当别论
The entire budget of this baby is deferred against back-end profit.
2000 没得减了
It's still two grand.Take it or leave it.
好 你够狠的
I like you.You got cojones.
你该给我当助手 我就不用请他了
You should be producing pictures instead of this faggot.
不如你给我们当个配角吧
How would you like to be in one?
你当初跟我说 我还以为你开玩笑
I thought you were kidding when you mentioned it earlier.
你14号 11点来
No.You be here 11 a.m.,on the 14th,and you...
给我们当个配角
are in the movie,Mr.Eaves.
我们送你首映礼的门票
We'll give you tickets to the premiere...
你跟你的朋友就可以在大银幕上看到你
and all your pals can come along and see you up on the big screen...
那可是名扬千古的喔
as one of the undead.
但是 你的房租得等我们票房有收入再说
But,in return you waive the rent until the movie is in profit.
这叫做"权宜之计"
It's called a "satisfactory deferment."
如果电影卖得好
As zombie roles go,it's great.
你可是名扬千里啊
You get to eat Amanda Donohoe.
谢谢
Thank you.
笑一个
Cheese.
你用菠菜把馅包好
So you tie your filo parcels with the spinach strands.
之后呢?
And then you?
把它放在油里炸一下
Then you drop them in oil.
要用滚油 记得要滚油
That's searing hot oil,Danny.Searing hot oil.
- 你知道这对他来说很重要 - 什么
- You know this means a lot to him. - What?
我对他来说是很重要 他以为自己找到了亲生孩子
I mean a lot to him.He thinks he's found his only son.
他是个强盗 他只爱自己 他以前就那样狠的 现在也是一样
He's a bully and he loves himself.
要滚油 滚油
He bounced back once,he'll do it again.Hot oil.
那鸡在哪里
Show me the pheasant.
鸡呢?
Pheasant,come on.
- Danny 鸡要先塞好调料 - 塞好调料
- Danny,that should have infused. - Infuse.
- 鸡要塞好调料 - 好了 还有什么
- Yeah,infuse the pheasant. - Yeah,what's that say?
- 那好了 塞好调料 - 好的 写好了
- I got it,haven't I.Already put infused. - All right,fine.Good.
好的
All right.
要用什么调料
Which sauce do I use?
全都用吧
All of them.
- 不会太多了吧 - 不会 相信我 那会很好吃的
- You don't think that's too much? - No,trust me.It'll do the job perfectly.
记得塞好调料
Remember to infuse the pheasant.
啊 没时间了
Ash,we're getting tight for time.
搞的怎样
How's it coming along?
你不来烦我的话都要搞好了
It'll be a lot quicker if you didn't keep phoning me.All right?
不知道能不能赶上
This is going to be close.
你要去Wilson家开趴啊?
You going to the Wilson's party and all?
不 我去我儿子家 他叫Jimmy.
No.I'm visiting my son,Jimmy.
Jimmy 和Paula那小俩口?在顶楼吧
Jimmy and Paula?Top floor?
- 住得够高的 - 不是啊 是三楼
- Streuth,you'd best get climbing. - Third floor.
Jimmy Haworth?那是地址吗
Jimmy Haworth?Those your directions?
不是三楼 是九楼 他们搬了
Oh yeah,it's not 301,it's 901.That's their old address.
我见过你吗?你声音听起来好熟喔
Don't I know you?Your voice,is familiar.
是吗 常常有人跟我这样说 人人都说我像Michael Caine.
Well,I get that a lot.People say I sound like Michael Caine.
- 是吗 - 对啊
- Do they? - Yeah.
我不等了 我爬楼梯算了
I'm not waiting for this death trap,I'm taking the bloody stairs.
你以前住九楼后来搬到三楼
You used to live in 901 and then you moved to 301.
有个混蛋跟我说你住顶楼
Numb-nut sent me to the top floor.
他肯定搞错了
He's got it the wrong way round.
我们以前是住顶楼 后来搬了
We used to live on the ninth but there was plumbing problems.
- 你好吗Keyes? - 你好
- How are you,Mr.Keyes? - Hello.
还是想陪陪我们啊?
Still feel you can't leave us on our own?
对阿 反正我也没事
No,got no life of me own,mate.
也借此来感谢一下你跟chris
This is our way of saying thank you to Chris as well.
你没必要这样做的
You shouldn't have done all this.
我们还想弄得好一点呢
We wanted it to be perfect.
- 你来了?有好胃口吗 - 这是在哪?
- Hi,I hope you brought an appetite. - Where was this taken?
那是在伊斯特本,不是吗 亲爱的?
That was Eastbourne.Weren't it,love?
当时我们刚订婚
Just after we got engaged.
你没事吧 Johnny?你脸都红了
You alright,Johnny?You're looking a little bit peaky.
要是能吃上顿美味的晚餐就什么事都好了 我们今晚吃什么?
Nothing a good supper won't cure.What are we eating?
好了 首先声明一下
Okay,now you got to bear in mind that...
我只在一家小餐馆做
I am working in the confines of a very small domestic kitchen.
别谦虚
Don't give me that.
来 坐一下 你也不要去偷看别的厨师做菜了
Come on,Johnny,you know better than to go poking round another chef's kitchen.
坐下 来喝一杯
Here,you sit down.I'll get you a nice drink.
你得找个女朋友了
You need to get yourself a girlfriend.
他一在厨房里就兴奋的要命
He's never happier than when he's playing in that kitchen.
油要滚 油要滚
Hot oil.Hot oil.
他就是这样被刺杀的
That's in case he gets a puncture.
快好了
All right for some.
那是什么味道
What's that smell?
我在煮大蒜
It's,well,roasting some garlic.
煮还是在偷吃啊?
Roasting or obliterating?
做的好
Well done,babes.
好了 尝尝
All right,bon appetit.
这灵感来自
Took my inspiration here from...
吉普赛人的做法
the Catalonian gypsy way of cooking the dish.
特意把鸡
Which is to present the bird...
烤焦
as over-basted.
我把这叫做
That's what I like to call...
乞丐鸡
"Peasant Pheasant."
看上去满好吃的
It looks really good.
我来切
Shall I carve?
试试那酱汁
Try the sauce.
觉得怎样
What do you think's in it?
太浓了
Too much.
好了 要来杯白兰地吗
Right,anyone care for a brandy?
我不要
No,I'm fine.
我要点
Well,I'd love one.
我也要点
Why not?
Johnny 你帮我拿一下吧 就在顶架上
I don't suppose you could reach up to the top shelf could you,Johnny?
没有了
This bottle's empty.
我下去买吧
Well I'll just nip over to the offy then,shall I?
很快就回来
Won't take me five minutes.
Chris 你陪她去吧 一个人去不大好
Lovely,sweetheart,would you go with her,Chris?
好的 没事吧?
Yeah,yes.Is anything wrong?
没事 桌子我们来收就好了
We'll clear the table for you.
你的确跟我很像
There's a lot of me in you.
你有梦想 你也有那个模样 你也有尊严
You got the dreams,and you got the patter,and you got the pride.
但你也跟我一样 很爱吹牛皮
And you got the bullshit.I should know.
我想私底下跟你谈谈
I wanted to say this to you in private.
我尊重你 所以我也坦白跟你说
And I'll do you the honor of speaking plainly.
你还厨艺不行
You ain't got it,son.
你有热情 能凑合弄顿晚餐
You're passionate about your food and you can rustle up a meal.
但你还不行
But you ain't got it.
如果我厨房好一点 工具好一点
If I had a proper kitchen.You know,if I had the right gear.
好厨师就算在旅行车上也能做出好饭菜
A good chef can whip up a gourmet meal on a hot car bonnet.
你做的配料比例都不对
You're slapdash about your ingredients.
太多调味了
You throw too many flavors at it.
调味太多而技巧又不够
Too many ingredients and not enough skill.
我要是还借钱给你
Now,I could throw a load of cash at you anyway.
你也是不会要的
But you wouldn't accept it...
因为你还是很有尊严跟原则的
because you got principles and pride.
我很欣赏你这一点
And I respect that more than you'll ever know.
- Johnny. - 跟我来
- Look,Johnny. - Come with me.
等一下 再给他们5分钟
Hang on.Let's just give them a few more minutes.
你在哪弄到这酒的
Where did you get this Madeira?
在哪弄到的 Jimmy?
Where did you get it,Jimmy?
那天我跟他们回家
You know the day I tracked them down...
我还以为那就是我的亲生父母
those people that I thought were my parents...
他们后来却不让我进屋
they wouldn't even let me in the house.
我才知道他们不要我了
That's when I found out that they'd dumped me.
他们给了赎金 却发现
They paid the kidnappers good money for me,only to realize that I was...
我是你的孩子
your boy.That was it.
就不要我了
They didn't want me anymore.
我那天再去到他们那
I came back that night.
当时我很生气
I was so angry.
之后
So...
我把那地方砸了
I just trashed the place.
那你干吗拿了这酒?
Why did you take the bottle?
因为那狮子
Because of the lion.
我记得我床上挂着的狮子
Lions were my first memory.
可能也是因为那样 我才会那么倔强
Guess that's where I get all my pride from.
Samuel?
这是手制的瓶子 年份是20世纪初的 你看那封口就知道
It's a molded bottle.Early 20th century.You can see the seam.
在这背后还写着 "B 1936 HMS."
Here on the back."B 1936 HMS."
是在1936 Boal vintage的 一个叫H.M.Sortiz的人做的
It's a 1936 Boal vintage produced by H.M.Sortiz.
没开封过
No revenue stamp.
我听不懂
I don't get it.
这软木没有用蜡封住
The stopper cork has no wax cover.But that's not surprising...
所以有些发霉了 还长了些虫子
the cork itself has been infested.Maggots got right into it.
里面的酒都沉淀了
The wine itself is lying low shoulder.
当然不能喝了
It's undrinkable.
但是你也不会打算要去喝这酒
But then,you'd never dream of opening this Madeira.
为什么?
Why not?
这酒是在西班牙封瓶的
This particular vintage was transferred to the Spanish mainland...
可能用运它船来命名这酒
and bottled there.Probably given the name of the ship that brought it.
里昂 就是狮子
Leon.The Lion.
这瓶身有些刮花了
But it's the etching here,in the glass itself.
最厉害的是这了
Now that's amazing.
"F.F."
什么意思
So?
这酒 可是用来献给
What you are holding is a Madeira that was presented...
Francisco Franco将军的
to General Francisco Franco.
在1936年十月
On the day he was made commander-in-chief of the Spanish Army...
他被升为将军的时候送给他的
in October,1936.
"F.F."
这东西是你养父母买来做投资的
Those scum you thought were your parents bought this as an investment.
现在它变成你的了
Now,it's your investment.
那家伙有钱不赎他孩子
This bloke's not looking to make money,is he?
非要让人把他孩子带走
He's looking to give it away.
我们给他来了场亲情戏
So we spin him a sob story.
应该还不够吧
But will that be enough?
要让他心肝情愿给钱给我们
Because giving Danny the money has to be his idea.
我想这会比DNA测试更能说服他的
I mean,that should convince him more than any blood test.
让他自愿借钱我投资
So the son persuades him to invest in a restaurant.
就是说我要去学做菜
That will mean that I got to learn to cook...
那可是太难了
which does sound far too much like hard work.
我们要在其他方面骗到他钱
We need him to pay up in cash.
那 这值好几千吧
So,is it worth a few quid?
对啊
Oh,yeah.
我好久没遇过这种好事了
I ain't felt this ruddy good in years.
你跟Paula该要开始一种新的生活了 我也该帮帮你们了
You and Paula deserve a start in life and you deserve something from me.
作为这么多年的补偿
To make up for not being there for you.
你不想我帮你 好没问题
You don't want handouts.Fine.
我就把这酒买了
I'll buy this bottle of wine off you.
120吧?
Call it 120?
- 120块啊? - 120万
- 120 quid? - 120 grand.
别大惊小怪的 这值这个数
It ain't charity,son.It's what it's worth.
要用来拍卖的话我还能赚一笔
I might even make a slim profit at auction one day.
不是吧
Yeah?
你真给我那么多啊?
So you can give me the money fair and square?
这是生意嘛
It's business.
120万
A hundred and twenty grand?
我以前也见过你这笑容
I've seen that smile on your face once before.
当时你牵着我的小指头
When you first held my little finger.
我们现在才相认还不太晚
It's not too late for me to be a dad to you,is it?
你跟我啊
You and me,boy.
你跟我
You and me.
都是强者
We're kings.
我们是万物之王
Kings of the ruddy jungle.
没错
Yeah.
来
Come on!
Johnny?
怎么回事
What's wrong?
得骗得过老行家
It has to fool a trained eye.
想个法子把这软木瓶盖搞一下
Find a way of rotting the cork.
弄点虫子放进去
Get maggots into it.
用点腐肉就好了
Rancid meat should do it.
把瓶子弄的好像久经风霜的
Age the bottle.
用它来鱼目混珠
An expert will know if it doesn't feel right.
要弄的像真的一样
Every detail has to be perfect.
- 捡回来 - 不要 算了吧
- Get it. - No.Leave it.
- 别让它毁了 - 算了吧
- Save it. - No.Leave it.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
你不会死的 我叫救护车
You're not gonna die.I'm just gonna call an ambulance.
我 我说过好多谎
I've done....I've been....So many lies.
我说过太多了
I've told so many lies.
你都是被逼的 你也不想的嘛
Look,you did what you had to do,didn't you?
你不会明白的 我当时够钱的
You don't understand.I had the money.
什么?
What?
我够钱付赎金的
I had the ransom to pay the kidnappers.
但是我跟他们说 说我没有
But I kept it.
我把钱用来做生意
I called their bluff.It was my money to get started.
我说了谎 之后就失去了你
I took a risk and I lost you.
因为我只想着我的生意
'Cause I wanted the business.
原谅我
Forgive me,son.
我说谎了
I'm a liar...
我骗了你
and a cheat.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我原谅你
I forgive you...
爸
Dad.
这真是精彩极了
It was a work of art,Ash.
你没事吧 Danny?
You all right,Danny?
我知道他是个坏人 还说谎
I know he was a bully and a liar but...
但我也骗了他阿
I lied to him,too,didn't I?
他死的时候听到的都不是真话
The last thing he heard before he died was a lie.
我们不仅仅说谎
We don't just lie to people,Danny.
我们说的都是他们想听的
We tell them what they want to hear.
我们还努力的
And for a moment...
把谎话变得想真的一样
they're truly happy.
好了 让我们看一下 可以吧?
So,can we see it,please?
当然可以
Absolutely.
他用尽力气把这拣回来了
He rescued it,you know.With his last ounce of strength.
他自死也是个强人
He was a strong man.
强人还不是死了?
Weak in other ways.
120万
One hundred and twenty grand.
我给你钱是因为Johnny 想这样做
I'm doing this because it's what Johnny wanted.
- 感谢你所做的一切 - 我也有个条件
- Thanks for everything you've done. - Now this is what I want.
你走吧
I want you to leave.
别再来烦我
Live your happy little lives and don't bother me again.
我还要做生意呢
I've got a business to sell off.
你干吗会做两个?
So why did you bother making a back-up?
以防万一嘛
As a back-up.
对不起 Mickey.我知道我一直让你们难做
I'm sorry,Mickey.I know I haven't been easy.
你朋友死了
You lost a friend,Albert.
伤心可以
It's okay to grieve...
但没必要不理我们
but don't shut us out.
Keyes死了也没什么遗憾的
You know,Keyes died well,didn't he?
他以为他儿子原谅他了嘛
Thinking that his son had forgiven him.
可能Gil死的也没什么遗憾的
Maybe old Gil died well,too.
都完成自己的心愿了
Doing what he loved.
我不知道 可能我想太多了
I don't know,maybe I worry too much.
生命是没终点的
There is no destination in life.
过程才是最重要的
The journey is everything.
什么?
What?
你有时候
It's just,the things you come out with sometimes,Albert.
你还蛮给我们鼓励的
You're still an inspiration,you know that?
像老爸一样?
Father figure?
我想是像爷爷一样吧 好了 谈一下guru吧
I was thinking more grandfather figure.Okay,what about guru?
guru 好的
Now guru,I like.
没什么好怕的
And there's nothing to be scared of.
我们不是还在一起嘛
We're all in this together.To the end.
你没事吧 我没见到你
You okay,mate?I didn't see you.
没事 扶我一下
Yeah,just need a hand.
捐献点?
For the poor?
好的
Yes.Of course.
你用钱买不了通往天国的路的
My son,you cannot buy your way into the Kingdom of Heaven.
只是表表心意罢了
Just playing the percentages,sweetheart.
到时片子上演了 你就知道我在干吗了
We'll soon see who's laughing when Amanda Donohoe gets here.